Valentino Urbano

Via Volta 10 – Rho (MI) – Italy (+39) 3389923193

valentino@valentinourbano.com http://valentinourbano.com

Github | LinkedIn | Twitter

Skills

iOS Dev:

Objective-C, Swift, Cordova, Unity, Xcode, Appcode, Cocoa, Cocoa Touch, SQLite, GCD, AVFoundation, Map-Kit, Navigation, AR, ARKit ML, MLKit, Realm, OAuth 2, Cryptography, Certificate Pinning, Animations, MapKit, REST, JSON, XML, SOAP, Unit Testing, UI Testing, UI Testing, Warthage, Swift Package Manager

Android Dev:

Android Studio, Java, Kotiir

WebDev (Frontend):

HTML 5, CSS3, Javascript, PHP, Word press

WebDev (Backend):

LAMP, Magento, Magento REST, php myadmin, SQL, SSL, Jekyll, MySQL MongoDB, Postgres SQL

DevOps:

SSH, SSH Keys, FTP, VPN, Bash, Linux (Debian, CentOS, Linux Lite, Fedora Ubuntu), NAS, Network configuration HDD recovery

Source Control:

Git, Git Flow, SVN, Continuos Integration

Design:

Adobe XD, Sketch, Gimp, ImageMagick

Pandoras

Integrating Pandora's box (mapping)

Miscellaneous:

Word, Excel, Google Docs, Python, C#, Ruby, Unity.

Summary

Gender Male | Day of Birth 22/08/1993 | Nationality Italian

I work developing apps for iOS, web applications and DevOps. I've been writing online since 2007 and I have had a website since 2009. I currently write on my Blog. I also work on some personal projects, write and play guitar.

I qualify for the O1 visa.

Work history

March 2018 – Current

January 2016 – March 2018

September 2014 –

December 2015

Freelancer

Italy

- Development of interactive system for an event for Monaco GP, including a mobile application, rest services and an exclusive social network.
- Development, analysis, deployment, roll out and support of a system (software/hardware) for Volkswagen to revolutionize the sale process inside and outside the dealerships. Currently rolled out to 6+ dealerships with plans to go nationwide. Mentioned in numerous national newspapers.

Lead (iOS) Developer

3Wlab SRL, Roma

- Development, analysis and prototyping of a Digital Shopping Experience for Moncler.
- Development and support of a banking application for Banca Intesa which won the "Best Finance Application of 2017" and "Best Finance Application of 2018" awards. 1M+ downloads, constantly top 3 in finance category (Italian Store).
- Development of 6 applications for Italian and International partners in different areas of business, from medical to tourism.

Freelancer

Remote, Poland

 Development of around 15 iPhone/Mac applications as personal projects as well as freelance contracts for various businesses.

Education

September 2012 – November 2014

September 2007 – July 2012

Computer Science

Università Statale di Milano, Italy

Aeronautical Expert Diploma ISS JC Maxwell, Milano

Competencies

Languages
Driving License
Other information

Italian, English (CAE Certificate), Polish, Spanish B, International

Extensive experience working remotely in a distributed team, strong self-learning skills, defined projects architecture and scope with final client, managed multiple development teams. Obtained ultra light flight piloting licence.